MOMIN BIN SHAHID

<SOFTWARE-ENGINEER/>



Education

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Bronze Medalist (BSCS) 2014 - 2017 University Of Karachi - Karachi, Pakistan U.O.K Merit Scholarship Holder

Technical Skills

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript (ECMAscript) and TypeScript
- HTML/HTML5 and CSS/CSS3
- SuiteScript 2.x
- SCSS & LESS
- SQL
- Markdown

CLOUD PLATFORMS

- AWS
- Firebase (GCP)
- NetSuite (ERP)
- Azure

FRONT-END FRAMEWORKS

- ReactJS
- VueJS
- Gatsby.js
- Angular

BACK-END FRAMEWORKS

- Node.js
- · Rhino.js

TESTING FRAMEWORKS

Mocha/Chai

DATABASES

- DynamoDB
- ElasticSearch
- MongoDB
- MySQL

DEVOPS

- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Helm

Jira

ADDITIONALLY;

- Express.js
- Vuetify/Ant Design
- Bootstrap
- WordPress
- JQuery

- Github/Bitbucket
- Puppeteer
- Redux/VueX
- Electron
- Serverless
- ESlint/Prettier

Profile

A Full-Stack JavaScript engineer with a bachelor's degree in computer science along with experience of 4 years in software development and 1.5 years in sales, marketing and customer management. Building solutions on the web for clients from all over the world, with multiple service-based and product-based companies

My expertise includes various domains including Internet Privacy and Security, Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP), Human Resource Management System (HRMS), E-learning for the Educational sector, Bioinformatics project with UCLA, IoT based solutions and many more. Most of my clients belonged to the USA while some belonged to Europe, the Middle East, and other parts of the world

In my career, I have been involved in fast-paced learning of emerging and legacy technologies, deeply assessing and understanding current systems, building web apps from scratch, dealing with clients directly, mentoring fellow engineers and leading decision-making throughout the software development lifecycle (SDLC) following industry's best practices to produce highquality results on time. As of now, I have only worked on closed-sourced projects but lately, I have started contributing to open-source software development (OSS)

Experience

SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Sep.2020 - Present

SECURITI.AI (FOUNDRI PVT. LTD.) - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Developing front-end using Vue.js (with Vuetify) for different modules within the product
- Building back-end as RESTful APIs in Node.js (with Express.js) using the microservices architecture with Docker in Kubernetes managed by Helm
- Execute development tasks and mentor fellow engineers on a daily basis and contribute to planning product features and enhancements for future sprints using SCRUM

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug.2019 - Sep.2020

FOLIO3 PVT. LTD. - KARACHI. PAKISTAN

- Operated as a Technical Consultant for Oracle NetSuite ERP developing full-stack solutions using SuiteScript 2.0 for customizing ERP functions and automating tasks
- . Interact with clients directly by providing technical support, performing troubleshooting and resolving customer issues
- · Alongside customizations, developed an HRMS from the ground up for Netsuite using React.js (with Ant Design) on the front-end and for the back-end we build RESTful APIs using NetSuite core modules by porting a Node.js (Express.js) server along with MongoDB as database

SOFTWARE ENGINEER I & II

Mar.2018 - Aug.2019

SCAYLE PVT. LTD. - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Worked as a full-stack developer for the U.S. based clients on School Management System, Bioinformatics research project with UCLA, IoT based solutions
- Developed new projects from square one and managed maintenance products. Deliver solutions utilising cloud infrastructure with AWS and Azure for UCLA project using Node.js
- Developed numerous web apps using React.js with Ant Design, Angular 2+ with Material

WEB DEVELOPER

Oct.2017 - Dec.2017

REMATCH STUDIOS (ADAMJEE TECH VENTURE) - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

· Created a website and social platform base for a game development studio using WordPress as CMS for their one-page website and blog

CUSTOMER RELATIONSHIP MANAGER

Dec.2015 - Mar.2016

AASHMAN TRADE AND LOGISTICS - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Looked after freight and other business affairs
- Managed the firm's website and portals via WordPress and custom code (HTML/CSS/JS)
- · Generated sales and business through aggressive marketing and sales strategies to achieve or exceed assigned sales targets

SALES AND MARKETING EXECUTIVE

Dec.2014 - Mar.2016

SEA LICENSING - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Managed agency's website via WordPress
- · Offered consulting, crew licensing, ship registration and other professional services to the seafarers within the international maritime rules & regulations